<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CJB</title>
    <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CJB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Airbnb Analytics</title>
      <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/airbnb/</guid>
      <description>Initiation We will be analyzing AirBnB listing data to create a model to predict the total cost for two people staying 4 nights in AirBnB in Mexico City.
# download the data listings &amp;lt;- vroom::vroom(&amp;quot;http://data.insideairbnb.com/mexico/df/mexico-city/2020-06-20/data/listings.csv.gz&amp;quot;)  Exploratory Data Analysis First we will conduct an Exploratory Data Analysis to better understand our data, understanding the number of columns, rows, type of observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session 2: Homework 1</title>
      <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/alcohol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/alcohol/</guid>
      <description>Where Do People Drink The Most Beer, Wine And Spirits? Back in 2014, fivethiryeight.com published an article on alchohol consumption in different countries.
# import data library(fivethirtyeight) data(drinks) Data Description - What are the variable types? Any missing values we should worry about?
ANSWER:
There are 4 numerics: beer_servings, spirit_servings, wine_servings and total_litres_of_pure_alcohol and 1 charcter: country.
No missing values based on the data.
# initial data exploration glimpse(drinks) ## Rows: 193 ## Columns: 5 ## $ country &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Afghanistan&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Albania&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Algeria&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;An… ## $ beer_servings &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 0, 89, 25, 245, 217, 102, 193, 21, 261, … ## $ spirit_servings &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 0, 132, 0, 138, 57, 128, 25, 179, 72, 75… ## $ wine_servings &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 0, 54, 14, 312, 45, 45, 221, 11, 212, 19… ## $ total_litres_of_pure_alcohol &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session 2: Homework 1</title>
      <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/stocks/</guid>
      <description>Returns of financial stocks We will use the tidyquant package to download historical data of stock prices, calculate returns, and examine the distribution of returns.
We must first identify which stocks we want to download data for, and for this we must know their ticker symbol; Apple is known as AAPL, Microsoft as MSFT, McDonald’s as MCD, etc. The file nyse.csv contains 508 stocks listed on the NYSE, their ticker symbol, name, the IPO (Initial Public Offering) year, and the sector and industry the company is in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon.</title>
      <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/blogs/soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/blogs/soon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/alg_trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/projects/alg_trading/</guid>
      <description>Mean reverse pairs trading strategy - Investment Fundamentals (Group 34) Mean Reversion strategy using Pair trading is one of the most popular hedge funds investment strategies. As markets are constantly shifting in and out of the mean reversal cycles, this strategy bets that prices will return to the average or mean.
Members: Muhammad Nauman Alam Khan, Tom Invernizzi, Rayna Zhang, Jerome Billiet, Christopher Baumann
# import required libraries import numpy as np import pandas as pd import statsmodels import statsmodels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/cv/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjbcoding.netlify.app/cv/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am a Master in Financial Analysis (MFA2021) student at London Business School.
Before starting my masters program here in London, I studied Business Administration at the University of St. Gallen in Switzerland. After, graduating in 2018, I took an extended GAP year to gain more experience in all the field that fascinate me. Therefore, I started with a four-month Data Science Bootcamp at ETH Zurich where I developed together with a physicist a AI-based prediction platform for time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
